Contact

00966504906605 (Mobile) musabbeham@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/alialmusabbeh-a22bb8105 (LinkedIn) www.vro.meim.gov.sa (Company)

Top Skills

Microsoft Office Leadership Team Building

Certifications

Corporate Communication
Safety & Health Award of Merit
PROSCI Change Management C
ertification

Ali Almusabbeh

Change Management Director - Strategy & Transformation Sector at SPL | سُبل

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

Summary

Experienced Change Director with a demonstrated history of working in the logistics and supply chain industry. Skilled in Microsoft Word, Balanced Scorecard, English, ISO Standards, and Total Quality Management (TQM). Strong consulting professional with a Bachelor's degree focused in Business Administration from King Faisal University.

Experience

SAUDI POST

Change Management Director December 2020 - Present (1 year 10 months)

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

VRO_MoEnergy (Vision Realization Office for the Energy Ecosystem)

Change Management Unit Head September 2019 - November 2020 (1 year 3 months)

Al-Riyadh Governorate, Saudi Arabia

CAREER AT A GLANCE:

- 15 Years in SABIC spent entirely in the Training & Development. Managed and designed different Technical, Safety, Leadership and Management Programs.
- 2 Years in SABIC Working Capital Optimization Project as a Change Management & Learning Team Member
- 2 years in SABIC MCE as Sr. Change Management & Learning Professional
- SABIC IMTYAZ Project Change Management Team Member
- Company Innovation & Best Achievements Forum Chairman
- Talent Development & Culture Transformation Project Leader
- Integrated Management System and RACI Project Leader
- SABIC Continuous Improvement Network Member

I have been the Acting Sr. Manager, Workforce Development & Continual Improvement several times during my tenure with SABIC. I have 22-Year

diversified experience in the areas of Workforce Development & Continual Improvement.

Between September 2018 I joined SABIC Manufacturing Project called: Operations Management System (OMS) in order to lead and deploy the change globally in SABIC affiliates and sites.

From September 2019 until November 2020, worked in the Vision Realization Office Energy Ecosystem held a position of Change Management Head and this is some of the achievements:

- 1. Developed change management plan for the Energy Ecosystem
- 2. Developed and designed a workshop for Non-Oil revenues
- 3. Lead an initiative to make VRO win a Great Place to Work
- 4. Developed Change Management Procedure
- 5. Developed department strategic objectives
- Participated in the assessment Maturity Level Assessment in 2019 and 2020.
- 8. Led and facilitated series of awareness session for the VRO Ecosystem entities
- 9. Developed performance improvement reward and recognitions system
- 10. Lead the development of Service Level Agreement
- 11. Initiated number of engagement/alignment sessions with external government entities
- 12. Contributed in development and implementation of Capabilities Building programs

SABIC

22 years

Continual Improvement Manager March 2016 - August 2019 (3 years 6 months) Jubail Industrial City

Change Management Senior Specialist May 2014 - February 2016 (1 year 10 months) Jubail Industrial City

Change Management Leader September 2012 - April 2014 (1 year 8 months) Al-Riyadh Governorate, Saudi Arabia

Training and Development Specialist

May 2006 - August 2012 (6 years 4 months)

Jubail Industrial City

Training Coordinator September 1997 - April 2006 (8 years 8 months)

Jubail Industrial City

Education

King Faisal University

Bachelor's degree, Business Administration · (2012 - 2016)